Part Two
Yes, yes, hello there, Araragi-senpai.
はいはいこんにちはですよ 阿良々木先輩
This is Ougi Oshino.
忍野扇です
Now today, we will be studying
about constellations.
では今日は 星座についてのお勉強をしましょうね
I realized right away
that this was a dream.
すぐにこれは夢なのだと気付いた
For Araragi-senpai, who lives in Japan, the
constellations in the southern skies may be difficult.
日本住まいの阿良々木先輩からすれば
南天の星座は厳しいでしょうね
Though my rival, Hanekawa-senpai, may perhaps
be looking at them now from around Australia.
私のライバルである羽川先輩は
ひょっとしたら今頃オーストラリアあたりでご覧になっているかもしれませんが
No, but really,
いや本当
the southern hemisphere has many unfamiliar
constellations, so it is amusing.
南半球には馴染みのない星座がたくさんありますから
面白いものですよ
There is Chameleon over that way.
あちらにはカメレオン座とかありますからね
There's also Pictor (easel) and Vela (sail).
あとは画架(がか)座とか 帆(ほ)座とか
There's even a constellation
called Hydrus (water snake).
水蛇(みずへび)座 というのもありますねえ
Water Snake
Snake—with a "water" radical
I guess it's what we would call
the Hydra (sea snake).
こちらで言うところの海蛇座でしょうかね
Surely you know of this one, the Hydra?
これはご存知ですよね 海蛇座
It's the biggest of the 88 constellations.
八十八の星座の中で 最大の星座です
Though, it's difficult to determine how the
size of a constellation is measured.
ま 星座の大きさをどういう風に計るかというのも
難しいところですけれどね
When you think of it three-dimensionally,
it pretty much falls apart.
立体的に捉えると 割とバラけちゃいますし
However, the presence
that this Hydra has...
ただ 海蛇座のこの存在感は
...reminds one of Kiss-shot
Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade.
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードを
連想させますよね
They call the creature
in Hydra a "sea snake",
そもそも海蛇座 海蛇とは言いますが
but it actually points to
the legendary hydras.
これは伝説上 ヒドラのことを示しているのです
Do you know what a hydra is?
わかりますか? ヒドラ
It's not an exaggeration
to say it's immortal.
不死身と言っても過言ではない
It's a monster that keeps regenerating
no matter how much you cut off.
斬っても斬っても再生する怪物です
The one that defeats that hydra is
the famous, courageous Heracles.
そのヒドラを退治するのは
有名な 勇猛な ヘラクレスなのですが
You probably cannot defeat Kiss-shot
Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade with this method,
このやりかたでは
キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードは倒せないでしょうが
but he chopped the nine heads
of the hydra one by one,
ヒドラの九つある首を順に斬り
and burnt the cut sections shut with a
flame to prevent them from regenerating.
切り口を炎で焼いて塞(ふさ)ぎ
再生できないようにしたのです
As a side note, during this fight
between Heracles and the hydra,
余談ですが この海蛇とヘラクレスとの戦いの際
the crab from Cancer sided with the
hydra and attacked Heracles.
海蛇の味方をしてヘラクレスを攻撃したのが
蟹座の蟹なのです
It used its big claws you know
of to cut at Heracles.
例の大きな鋏(はさみ)で
ヘラクレスに切りつけました
Its attitude of challenging a giant
enemy with a small weapon is,
小さな武器で大きな敵に挑む姿勢は
in fact, Senjougahara-senpai herself.
まさしく戦場ヶ原先輩そのものですね
When you awaken, please tell
Senjougahara-senpai about this episode,
目が覚めたらこの辺りのエピソードを戦場ヶ原先輩に話して
so that you can be well-liked.
是非とももててくださいよ
Serpens, the one that isn't Hydra,
そして 海蛇座ならぬ蛇座のほうも
is also a symbol of immortality,
though not as much as the hydra.
ヒドラでこそありませんが
不死身性の象徴ではありますからね
After all, Serpens has a special
characteristic that you can say
なにせ この蛇座というのは全天八十八星座の中でも
is unique among all 88
constellations in the sky.
唯一と言っていい
変わった特徴を持っていますからね
Do you know what it is, Araragi-senpai?
なんだかご存知ですか? 阿良々木先輩
I don't know.
Does Ougi-chan know what it is?
扇ちゃんは知っているのだろうか
I don't know anything.
私は何も知りませんよ
It's what you know, Araragi-senpai.
あなたが知っているんです 阿良々木先輩
In reality, you should know what it is.
御存知のはずですよ 本当は
See, like this.
ほら こういう風に
Serpens is the only constellation that exists
split up into the eastern and western parts.
蛇座は東西に分断されて存在する
ただひとつの星座なのです
As a snake... It has been chopped up.
蛇として ぶつ切りにされている
This clearly shows immortality.
これは 見るからに不死身ですよね
It's still alive despite its
body chopped in half.
身体を真っ二つにされても生きているだなんて
Well, Araragi-senpai, you seem to have your
body chopped into half rather often as well.
Actually, in the gap where it is split up, a
different constellation has been drawn in.
実を言いますと 分断されたその狭間には
別の星座が描かれているのですよ
I'm sure you know of it, Araragi-senpai,
but it's Ophiuchus (snake charmer).
これは絶対に阿良々木先輩はご存知だと思いますが
蛇遣い座です
The picture depicts the snake charmer
holding the upper and lower halves...
蛇遣いが 蛇の上半身と下半身を
...of the snake's body with his left
and right arms, respectively.
左腕右腕でそれぞれ持っているという図になるのですよ
If I recall, that snake charmer was
Asklepios, dubbed the sage physician?
確か あの蛇遣いは医聖と呼ばれる
アスクレピオスなのだっけ?
Sage physician
That's right. Nothing less from you,
Araragi-senpai. You really have extensive knowledge.
そうですね さすが阿良々木先輩
博識でいらっしゃる
Asklepios' medical skills were
honed remarkably quickly,
アスクレピオスの医術の技は
めきめきと洗練され
and it got to a point where he
could even resurrect the dead.
しまいには死人さえも蘇(よみがえ)らせるレベルにまで達したのです
However, that was going too far.
けれど これはやり過ぎだった
Going too far. Against the rules.
やり過ぎ ルール違反
I guess you could say it went
against the logic of the world.
世の理(ことわり)に反すると言いますかね
Bringing forth anger of Hades
the god of the underworld,
冥王(めいおう)ハーデスの怒りを買い
Asklepios was struck by lightning
and literally sent to heaven.
アスクレピオスは雷に打たれて
文字通り天に召されたというわけです
Well, bringing a person back to life -- to
mass-produce immortals -- is quite the sin.
まあ 人を生き返らせるというのは
不死身を量産するというのは 結構な罪ということですよ
Yotsugi Ononoki-chan is also among those
who were resurrected after death, but...
斧乃木余接ちゃんも
死後に生き返らされた一人ではありますが
Tadatsuru Teori
All parties responsible for
her resurrection faced retaliation...
彼女を生き返らせた当事者は全員
そのしっぺ返しで
Yoduru Kagenui
Meme Oshino
Deishu Kaiki
...and had curses placed
upon their bodies.
その身に呪いを受けましたからね
Hm? What's this about?
Curses?
If that's the case, what's
going to happen?
となるとどうなんでしょうねえ
What kind of penalty will Gaen-san pay in the
future for reviving Araragi-senpai from hell?
阿良々木先輩を地獄から復活させた臥煙さんは
今後一体どんな報いを受けることになるのでしょうねえ
Izuko Gaen
Ha-hah...
はっはー
Ougi-chan, if you're going to sit
down, sit on my left side.
扇ちゃん 座るなら左側に
Hmm? Why is that?
どうしてです?
That's Senjougahara's seat.
そこは戦場ヶ原の席だから
My oh my, that is not a cheap seat.
おやおや これはお安くありませんねえ
Well, please don't worry.
まあ ご心配なく
I have never had any intentions of taking
over the throne of the main heroine.
私はメインヒロインの座を脅(おびや)かそうというつもりは毛頭ありませんよ
I wouldn't mind striving to be a
"little sister" character...
妹キャラくらいなら目指してもいいところですが...
But, Karen-chan aside, I wouldn't want
to compete against Tsukihi-chan.
しかし火憐ちゃんはともかく
月火ちゃんとは競いたくはありませんかねえ
She is... Her true identity is...
彼女は... 彼女の正体は
Tadatsuru Teori said it.
手折正弦は言った
He told me at the bottom of hell.
地獄の底で僕に教えてくれた
He mentioned the name of the client who
requested him to exterminate me and Shinobu...
彼は 僕や忍の退治を依頼したクライアントの名を...
Araragi-senpai. What do you
think is the right thing?
阿良々木先輩 正しさってなんだと思います?
Oh no, you don't have to think
too seriously about it.
It is difficult to be
doing the right thing.
正しいことをするというのは 難しいですからね
It is especially difficult to
do "just the right thing."
特に "正しいことだけをする" というのは
とても難しいです
If you try to do the right thing, you
end up also having to do attachments,
正しいことをしようとすると
付属して 間違ったこと
wrong things or things that are not right.
正しくないこともしなくちゃあならなくなったりします
So that's why, Araragi-senpai.
だからですね 阿良々木先輩
To win, there is an absolute need
to lose somewhere along the way.
As long as you are being the right self,
you should not be doing the right thing.
正しい自分である上では
正しいことをするべきではないんですよ
In the end, if a mistake always accompanies
you when you try to do the right thing,
正しいことをしようとすれば
必ずそこに間違いが伴う
and if that's the case...
というのであれば...
In the end it all balances out to zero.
結局差し引きゼロになってしまいますからね
Therefore, the way of life that Kagenui-san
and the Fire Sisters practice
ですから 影縫さんやファイヤーシスターズが
実践している生きざまは
is something they claim to be justice.
彼女達自身は正義を名乗っていますけれど
But, it is not necessarily
"doing the right thing."
決して "正しいことをしている" わけではありません
To stay the right selves, they
do not do the right thing,
彼女達は正しい自分であるために
正しいことをするのではなく
MISTAKES
but correct mistakes...
間違いを正す...
INJUSTICE
... and correct injustice. That is
the way of life they choose.
不正を正す...
そういう生き方を選んでいるのです
EXAMINE (tadasu)
Examine (tadasu)...
糺す あるいは問い質す
とも言いますがね
...or Inquire a question (toi-tadasu),
I guess you could say.
INQUIRE (tadasu)
In other words, your foe's foe is not your
ally, but by becoming a foe against evil,
つまり 敵の敵は味方ではありませんけれど
悪の敵となることで
by becoming the antonym to evil, you
assign yourself justice, so to say.
悪の対義語となることで
己に正義を任ずるということですかね
And I am also one that seeks the type
of "right" that corrects mistakes.
そして私もまた 間違いを正すタイプの
正しさを追い求める者です
It is my role to eject those
that have broken the rules.
ルール違反をした者に退場を命じるのが
私の役割です
TO SCATTER (kakusan)
Broken the rules...
ルール違反...
TO DISPERSE (musan)
...ejection.
退場
Araragi-senpai, the program
is about to end.
阿良々木先輩
そろそろプログラムが終わります
It's better for you to
wake up now, isn't it?
目を覚ましたほうがいいですよ?
You should at least continue to enjoy
恋する相手とのデートを
the rest of your date with the
person you're in love with.
この後も精々楽しんできてくださいよ
But, since you have the
chance, Araragi-senpai...
でも 折角ですから阿良々木先輩
Please think about the answer to
the question of what you think
正しさってなんだと思うかという問いの答は
is the right thing when you
have to kill some time.
暇潰しに考えておいてください
Let's talk about it again when
I see you in real life.
現実世界で会ったときに
それについてお話ししましょう
Yeah, I got it.
If I still remember when I wake up.
But really, what in the world
is your true identity?
だけどきみは本当に何者なんだい?
That too will be discussed
the next time I see you.
それも またお会いしたときにお話しさせてもらいますよ
But well, if I were to force myself to
say what I can say at this moment...
まあでも 今 言える限りのことを強いて言うなら
I am...
私は...
...the principles of the universe.
宇宙の法則ですよ
Space map...
宇宙地図...
...in the shape of a hand fan (ougi).
扇の形
Pitch black vacuum...
and unbalanced galaxies.
真っ黒な真空に... 偏った銀河
Don't think about this too hard, either.
これも深く考えないでください
Now that you came back from hell, and returned
to being completely human, Araragi-senpai...
地獄から蘇り
今や完全なる人間に戻った阿良々木先輩とは
Surprisingly enough, I may no longer have to be
concerned with you anymore... if things go well.
案外私は これ以上関わらずに済むかもしれませんから
あわよくば
So, please.
ですから
I beg of you, don't get suckered
into Gaen-san's slick talk.
お願いですから 臥煙さんの口車に乗らないでくださいね
Concerning Kiss-shot Acerola-orion
Heart-under-blade now in her complete form,
完全体となったキスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードや
or Mayoi Hachikuji who has,
after resting in peace, returned again,
成仏しておきながら またもこの世に舞い戻った
got lost again, within this world...
迷い戻った八九寺真宵について
This time, I expect, from
the bottom of my heart,
今度こそ "見捨てる" という正しい判断をされることを
that you'll make the right
decision to forsake them...
私は心から期待しますよ
Araragi-senpai.
阿良々木先輩
I woke up.
I woke up?
Senjougahara....
戦場ヶ原...
I'm not asleep.
寝てないわ
I'm not asleep at all.
全然寝てない
I'm not asleep at all. I was just
thinking with my eyes shut.
全然寝てない
目を瞑(つむ)って考え事をしていただけ
I'm sorry. I was actually asleep.
ごめんなさい 本当は寝ていました
It's fine. I was asleep for a bit, too.
大丈夫 僕もちょっと寝ちゃってたから
I see. I guess it means
we were both tired?
そう お互い疲れていたということかしら
I guess it was too hasty to go on a date
after we only decided on it yesterday.
さすがに昨日の今日でデートというのは
突貫工事過ぎたわね
So, what kind of plans did
you have after this?
で ここから先はどういう予定になっているんだ?
We're going to learn the state-of-the-art
science at the adjoining science museum.
併設の科学館で現代の最新鋭の科学を学ぶのよ
After doing a tour of the science
museum, we'll have lunch.
科学館を一周したあとは 昼食よ
The plan was to study during the morning,
午前中はお勉強プランだったから
Floor Map
so I have mainly leisurely activities
planned for the afternoon.
午後は遊びをメインに据えているわ
We'll go out to the city by car, and
spend the first half bowling.
クルマでちょっと町まで出て
前半はボウリング
After a bit of tea time, we'll spend
the second half singing karaoke.
ティータイムを挟んで 後半はカラオケよ
Oh...
Araragi-kun, what's your
high score in bowling?
阿良々木くん ボウリングのハイスコアは?
Well, I'm a novice at bowling altogether,
like I don't think I've ever played before.
いや ボウリング自体初心者で
たぶんやったことないと思うんだけど
Got it. There will be a
penalty on the loser.
わかった 負けたら罰ゲームね
Don't set up a penalty after it came
to light that I'm a novice!
僕が初心者と判明してから罰ゲームを設定するな
The loser must swear absolute
obedience to the winner.
敗者は勝者の命令に絶対服従
That's a really harsh penalty!
罰ゲームが重いよ!
Dammit... To think that Araragi-kun
would actually lie to me...
おのれ... まさか阿良々木くんが私に嘘をつくなんて
You're not a novice at all.
全然初心者じゃないじゃない
KOYOKOYO
HITAGI
From about the first frame
till about the fifth frame,
第一フレームから第五フレームあたりまでは
HITAGI
KOYOKOYO
she showed amazing skill.
見事な腕前だった
HITAGI
KOYOKOYO
However, starting at the sixth
frame, her playing...
しかし第六フレーム以降 彼女のプレイは
HITAGI
KOYOKOYO
LIMITS OF ACTIVITY
HITAGI
KOYOKOYO
...suddenly changed.
Completely changed...
一転した 一変した
Right.
そう 戦場ヶ原は疲れたのである
Senjougahara was exhausted.
Seems that her arm went numb.
腕が痺(しび)れたらしい
KOYOKOYO
HITAGI
Fine. I will admit defeat.
いいわ 負けを認めるわよ
You can order me to do anything.
なんでも命令するがいいわ
So, I wonder what kind of lewd
request will you make of me?
さあ どんなエッチな要求をしてくれるのかしら?
My anticipation only heightens.
期待は高まるばかりだわ
Just for reference, if you
had won, Senjougahara,
ちなみに戦場ヶ原が勝っていた場合は
what kind of request were
you going to make?
どんな要求をするつもりだったのか
I was going to make a lewd
request, of course!
当然 エロい要求をするつもりだったわよ!
I struck a deal with something like, "Then
let's walk arm-in-arm until our tea time."
じゃあティータイムまで
腕を組んで歩こうという辺りで手を打った
Hmm... To think that you were having an adventure of
that sort on the actual day of the entrance exams.
ふうん... まさか受験日当日に
そんなアドベンチャーを繰り広げていたとは
It's unexpected, but it's so
fitting for you, Araragi-kun...
意外と言うか
阿良々木くんらしいと言うか...
Though, I have to ask, what in
the world were you doing?
何をやっているんだと言うか
it's unclear exactly what Gaen-san
is fighting against...
臥煙さんが何と戦っているのかは定かではないけれども...
But perhaps you, Araragi-kun, are
the opponent of that battle.
ひょっとしたら それは
阿良々木くんを相手に戦っているのかもしれないわよね
No, it's more of a hunch than any meaning.
いえ 意味と言うよりは直感なんだけれども
Compared to your stance, Araragi-kun, where you
can only see what is right in front of your eyes,
目の前のことしか見えない阿良々木くんの姿勢とは
that macroscopic stance Gaen-san takes would
clash no matter how you look at it.
どうしたって臥煙さんの巨視的なスタンスは
対立しそうだなって
Clash... or oppose, if you want
a slightly harsher term.
対立 もう少し厳しく言うならば
敵対 かしら
We'll duke it out for two hours, and
the one who loses in total points...
二時間対決して
総合得点で負けたほうは勝ったほうに
Karaoke
Red-White Song Battle
...swears absolute obedience
to the winner.
絶対服従ね
Song: "Futakotome"
Setting: Original Key
I'll go first. You listen well.
先攻私 聞くがいいわ
Challenger: Hitagi-san                                            Song: Futakotome
Score: 82.107%
Analysis: You have very high singing skills,
but emotional expression seems slightly weak.
It will be better if you add
more intonation to your singing.
An 82...
82点
Lies.
嘘
82 percent is a failing score. This is the
first time I've ever scored in the low eighties.
82点って 赤点じゃない
生まれて初めて八十点台前半を取ったわ
What kind of test is it if 82
percent is a failing score?
82点が赤点って どんなテストだよ
Araragi-kun, you spent the majority of your
high school career feeling like this?
阿良々木くんは
高校生活の大半をこんな気分で過ごしてきたの...?
I was not able to understand it at all.
理解してあげられてなかったわ
I was supposed to be a lot kinder to you.
もっと優しくしてあげなきゃいけなかった
What kind of horrible things have
I been saying to Araragi-kun?
私はなんて酷いことを
阿良々木くんに言ってきたんだろう
You're saying those horrible
things right now.
酷いことは今言ってる
Song: chocolate
Setting: original key
Challenger: Koyokoyo-san                   Song: chocolate insomnia
Score: 82.438%
Analysis: All elements are coming together
at a very high level. Keep it up,
and 100% is not just a dream.
Loser - Red 819           RESULTS       Winner - White 822
And once again, I was the winner.
そして勝ったのはまたも僕だった
Impossible... To think that I would lose
against Araragi-kun twice in one day.
馬鹿な... この私が阿良々木くんに
一日のうちに二度も負けるだなんて
Now, feel free to give
me any order you want.
さあ 何でも命令するがいいわ
How about you carry me to
our car like a princess?
駐車場までお姫さま抱っこっていうのはどうかしら?
I'll kill you if you say I'm heavy.
重いって言ったら殺すからね
Nothing less from you, Araragi-kun.
さすが阿良々木くん
It shows that you're used to cradling young
girls in your arms in everyday life.
普段から幼女を抱っこし慣れているだけのことはあるわね
That particular expression
leads to misunderstandings.
I'd like you to stop that.
Hourly Parking
Entrance 50m ahead
Whew. That was embarrassing.
ふう 恥ずかしかった
I just saw hell.
地獄を見たわ
You'd go that far?
そこまで言うか
MORE HELLISH THAN HELL
Senjougahara....
戦場ヶ原...
I have something important to talk about.
大事な話があるんだが
If it's a request to get
married, I'm okay with it.
結婚の申し込みならＯＫよ
No, it's not that important a topic.
いや そこまで大事な話じゃない
And that was way too instant a reply.
そしてふたつ返事過ぎる
IT TURNED INTO A MARRIAGE PROPOSAL
Actually, it's about a gift in return for the
chocolate I received for Valentine's Day...
実は バレンタインデーに頂いた
チョコレートのお返しの件なんだが
I haven't been able to get one ready.
用意できてないんだ
I'm sorry. I didn't have
time to get one ready.
ごめんなさい 用意する時間がなかった
In thinking of what to get,
I thought way too much.
考えているうちに考え過ぎてしまって
HONEST MAN
So, can you wait two or three more days?
なので二 三日待ってはもらえないだろうか
THINKING TOO MUCH
Of course, I'll tack on the interest
accrued during that period.
もちろん その分の利息は上乗せするから
What, you were worried about such a thing?
なんだ そんなことを気に病んでいたの
It was enough for me that you went on
a date with me the whole day today.
今日一日 デートしてくれただけでも十分よ
It's fine for you to just give me
something when you feel like it.
気が向いたら何かくれるくらいでいいわよ
It wasn't like I made that chocolate
expecting to receive something in return.
私はお返しを期待してチョコレートを作ったわけではないわ
Araragi-kun.
阿良々木くん
It's unforgivable.
許せないわね
Eh?
I can't hardly believe that, on White Day,
one of the three big events of the year for couples,
あろうことか恋人達の三大イベントのひとつであるホワイトデーに
you don't have anything
prepared for your lover?
ラバーに対して何も用意していないだなんて
I have to doubt that you have
any affection towards me.
私に対する愛情を疑わざるを得ないわ
Eh? Ehh?
All day today, I was wondering exactly what
kind of surprise Araragi-kun had prepared for me.
今日一日 阿良々木くんはいったいどんなサプライズを用意してくれているんだろうと
My heart was racing, and I was so excited...
But you didn't have anything ready.
どきどきはらはらわくわくしていたのに
何の準備もなかっただなんて
What a sidestep that was!
肩透かしもいいところよ
I had assumed that you would get me a
cruiser or something as a present.
てっきり クルーザーの一台くらい
プレゼントしてくれるのかと思っていたのに
I-Isn't that expectation a bit too
mega-sized, don't you think?
そ それは期待がメガサイズ過ぎないかい?
Oh, brother. I wonder if I
should just kill myself.
あーあ 自殺しよっかなー
I-I'm sorry. That's why I'm apologizing.
ご ごめん だから謝ってるじゃん
Please don't commit suicide.
自殺はしないでください
T-Then, what can I do for
you to forgive me?
じゃ じゃあ どうすれば許してくれる?
I can't get you a cruiser, but
I'll do whatever I can-
クルーザーは用意できないけれど
できる限りのことなら
Did you just say you'll
do whatever you can?
できる限りのことをするって言った? 今
Did you say absolute obedience?
絶対服従って言った?
N-No, I didn't say that...
い いえ 言ってませんけれど...
I did, I did! Indeed, I did say "absolute
obedience" with these lips!
言いました 言いました 絶対服従と
まさにこの口で言いました
I see. Nothing less from you,
Araragi-kun. Such a generous heart.
そう さすが阿良々木くん
その度量の広さ
You really are the man
I fell in love with.
私が惚れた男ね
I've fallen in love with you over again.
惚れ直したわ
You don't know what I'm
going to request of you,
何を要求されるかもわからないのに
一生 私のお願いに絶対服従してくれるだなんて
but you're willing to be absolutely obedient
to my requests for the rest of your life.
The rest of my life!?
一生!?
S-Sure. The rest of my life.
お おう 一生だな
I got it. What should I do?
わかった 僕は何をすればいいんだ
Call my name.
名前で呼んで
Call me... by my name.
私のこと 名前で
Eh?
I do call you. "Senjougahara."
呼んでるじゃん 戦場ヶ原って
Not that. My first name,
with no honorifics.
じゃなくて 下の名前で 呼び捨てに
So that's why she tried to set up a
penalty for bowling and karaoke.
だからボウリングやカラオケで
罰ゲームを設けようとしていたのか
If it wasn't for an opportunity like this, it may
have been something I'd have never been able to say.
こんなきっかけでもなければ
言えないことだったかもしれない
Absolute obedience for
the rest of my life.
一生 絶対服従
Calling her by that name for
the rest of my life.
一生 その名を呼び続ける
...Hitagi.
ひたぎ
Thank you... Koyomi.
ありがとう 暦
ARARAGI
Hello, Araragi-senpai.
やあ 阿良々木先輩
I've been waiting for you.
お待ちしておりましたよ
I've gotten tired of waiting.
待ちくたびれました
I got exhausted just by waiting.
待つだけでくたびれました
How was it?
いかがでした?
Did you enjoy your last date
with Senjougahara-senpai?
戦場ヶ原先輩との
最後のデートは楽しめましたか?
At the least, I was being considerate and
avoided butting in over on the physical world.
一応気を遣って
現実世界での割り込みは控えておいたんですけれど
I'd like you to be appreciative of that.
感謝していただきたいものですねえ
I will be appreciative.
感謝はする
But, how you said "the last date"
creates misunderstanding.
ただ 最後のデートっていう言いかたは
誤解を招くな
It was merely the last date
of my high school life.
あくまでも 高校生活
最後のデートだ
So is it? Yes, that would be nice if it is...
It'd be nice if the two of you had a future.
です か ええ だったらいいですよねえ
お二人に 未来があればいいですよねえ
Ougi-chan. Did you try to exterminate me?
扇ちゃん きみは 僕を退治しようとしたの?
You asked a specialist to do such a thing?
そんなことを 専門家に依頼したの?
Oh, you heard from someone...
of such false rumors?
おや 誰かから聞きましたか? そんなデマを
But still, that is a sad false alarm...
しかしそれは悲しい誤報ですね
I would like an explanation.
釈明させて欲しいところです
There is no way I would do anything
to harm you, Araragi-senpai.
私が阿良々木先輩を
害するようなことをするわけがないじゃありませんか
That's why I told you, right?
だから言ったでしょう?
That I am expecting you, Araragi-senpai,
to make the right decision...
阿良々木先輩が正しい判断をして
...and withdraw, instead of getting
suckered into Gaen-san's slick talk.
臥煙さんの口車に乗ることなく
退(ひ)いてくれることを期待します と
Did you say that?
言ったっけな
Well...
If she is saying she said
it, she probably said it.
But, it's nonexistent. The choice of forsaking
Shinobu and Hachikuji is something I don't have.
だけど ないぜ
忍や八九寺のことを見捨てるなんて選択肢は 僕には
There is no choice. I have no
surplus within my heart.
選択の余地はない
僕の心に余りはない
I don't know what the right thing is, but
I do know what path I should take.
正しさが何かなんてわからないけれど
自分の選ぶべき道はわかっている
I wish you wouldn't hurry to
conclusions like that...
そう結論を急がないで欲しいものですけれど
But well, that's fine. I tried to ask you
because I had nothing left to lose.
でもまあ そうですね 私としても
駄目元で訊いてみただけです
That said, it's disappointing.
とは言え残念です
For me personally, I'd like to see you,
Araragi-senpai, retire voluntarily right about now.
私としては 阿良々木先輩には
ここらでご勇退願いたいんですけれどね
But egging you on to do so too much
would be going beyond my bounds.
あまりそれを促すのも
領分を出てしまいますか
Hey, Araragi-senpai.
ねえ 阿良々木先輩
Let me correct one thing that you may
have a misunderstanding about.
ひとつ あなたが勘違いされているかもしれないことを
訂正させてくださいよ
Misunderstanding? What is
the misunderstanding?
勘違い? 勘違いって... 何?
I am not the "darkness."
私は "くらやみ" ではありませんよ
By the way, Araragi-senpai.
ところで阿良々木先輩
Araragi-senpai, you've fallen to
hell, and you've gone on a date,
阿良々木先輩には 地獄に落ち
デートもして
so you may have nothing you look
back on with regret anymore.
もう思い残すことはないかもしれませんけれど
But I currently have one thing that I
look back on with regret in this town.
私には現在 ひとつ
この町で思い残していることがありましてね
Something you look back on with regret?
思い残していること?
Something you wouldn't
mind dying to achieve...
それをやり遂げるためなら死んでもいいし
Once you achieved this, you wouldn't mind if you died.
Do you have such a goal, Araragi-senpai?
それをやり遂げたら死んでもいいという目標が
阿良々木先輩にはありますか?
I have one. I have just one more.
私にはあるのです
あとひとつだけ あるのです
That's why I have to do it even if I
have to put everything else aside.
だから何をおいても
それをしなければならないのですけれど
That is why if Izuko Gaen, the leader of the
specialists, were to place a trap, it would be there.
だからこそ 専門家の元締め
臥煙伊豆湖が罠を張るとすれば そこなのでしょう
Yes, I know.
ええ わかっています
I know, but I still have
to fall for that trap...
わかっていても
その罠には引っかかるしかない
I have to resign myself to
suffer that counterattack.
その反撃を
私は甘んじて受けるしかない
In other words, starting right now, I am going to
fight the big sister that knows everything,
つまり 私はこれから 正面切って誤魔化しなく
何でも知ってるおねーさんと戦うことになるのですけれど
with a frontal assault,
with no fudging around...
Araragi-senpai, in this fight,
can you be on my side?
阿良々木先輩 そのときは
私の味方をしてくれませんか?
Please, help me.
私を助けてください